Welcome back to the the moment when we bring it all together into a beautiful user interface.
すべてを美しいユーザー・インターフェースにまとめる瞬間へ､ ようこそ｡
But first, just a quick look one more time at the inference endpoint screen in Huggingface where you
その前に､ もう一度Huggingfaceの推論エンドポイント画面を見てほしい｡
Quine 1.57 billion chat inference.
クワイン1 570億チャットの推論
We can.
我々はできる｡
I just wanted to show you that you can come into this and take a look at how your inference endpoint
分析結果を見たり､ 何が起こっているのかを見たり､
is running, and you can do things like see analytics, see what's going on, see the number of requests,
リクエスト数を見たりすることができます｡
Uh, latency, CPU usage.
ええと､ レイテンシー､ CPU使用率｡
Oh, there we go.
そうだ｡
A little blip in CPU usage from what we just did and GPU usage.
CPUの使用率とGPUの使用率が少し上がっている｡
Nice.
いいね｡
Uh, and you can also go over to cost and see that I've spent $3.64 so far on, uh, on this particular,
それと､ "コスト "を見て､ 僕が3ドル使っていることがわかると思う｡  これまでのところ､ この特定のモデルで64回｡
Um, okay.
うーん､ わかった｡
Now, with that in mind, let's leave it, I think, on the analytics, let's go back to our Jupyter
さて､ それを念頭に置いて､ アナリティクスは置いておいて､ Jupyterラボに戻ろう｡
Um, and let's wrap this code to call Code Kwan in a nice little stream method, just like the other
コード・クワンを呼び出すこのコードを､ GPT4やクロード・ストリーム・クエンですでにやった他のストリーム・メソッドと同じように､
stream methods that we've already done before for GPT four and for Claude stream Quen.
小さなストリーム・メソッドにまとめよう｡
Same kind of method, but of course it's the same function.
同じような方法だが､ もちろん同じ機能だ｡
It's going to do it very differently.
そのやり方はまったく違う｡
It's going to create a tokenizer.
これはトークナイザーを作成する｡
It's going to, of course, uh, turn Python into the usual messages list.
もちろん､ Pythonを通常のメッセージリストに変えることになる｡
It's going to apply the chat template.
チャットのテンプレートが適用されます｡
So we now have this in the text that is ready for tokenization.
これでトークン化の準備が整った｡
And then we make the magical call to inference client using the URL for our endpoint and passing in
そして､ エンドポイントのURLとHuggingfaceトークンを使って推論クライアントを呼び出します｡
And here we are doing client text generation.
そして､ ここではクライアントのテキスト生成を行っている｡
Here's our text we want to stream.
ここにストリーミングしたいテキストがある｡
And that's our max new tokens.
これが新しいトークンの最大値だ｡
And then back comes the results.
そして結果が戻ってくる｡
As we stream back each token we yield the total of everything so far because hopefully you remember
各トークンをストリームバックする際に､ これまでの合計を返す｡
It expects to a sort of cumulative total of everything that's been received so far in all of its chunks.
それは､ すべてのチャンクでこれまでに受信されたすべてのものの累積合計のようなものを期待している｡
So that function there stream collection is a companion function to the others we wrote before for stream
つまり､ このストリーム・コレクションという関数は､ 前に書いたストリームGPTのストリーム・クロードの関数と同じものなのだ｡
So now we can have an optimized method that will replace the previous optimized method for optimizing
これで､ コードを最適化するための､ 以前の最適化された方法に代わる最適化された方法を手に入れることができ､ 3つのモデルGPTクロードかコード・クワンの間で反転することができる｡
Um.
うーん｡
And here we have the total of our user interface code for Gradio.
そしてここに､ Gradioのユーザー・インターフェースのコードの合計がある｡
Make sure I run this.
これを必ず実行する｡
Uh, so you'll remember how simple this is.
ええと､ だから､ これがどれだけ簡単なことか思い出してほしい｡
It's crazy.
クレイジーだよ｡
Uh, we have a nice little title, and then we have a row for our Python code and C plus plus code.
タイトルをつけて､ PythonのコードとC＋＋のコードを並べます｡
We have a row for selecting the model.
モデルを選択する行がある｡
And now we've added code Kwon to the three to the previously two models that you could choose between.
そして今回､ これまで選べた2つのモデルにコード・クォンが加わった｡
And we've got a button to convert the code, a button to run Python, a button to run C plus plus,
コードを変換するボタン､ Pythonを実行するボタン､ C plus plusを実行するボタン､
and then some output boxes for the Python results and the cplusplus results.
そしてPythonの結果とcplusplusの結果の出力ボックスがあります｡
And then these are the three actions.
そして､ これが3つのアクションだ｡
The three places where if a button is clicked, we take some kind of action.
ボタンがクリックされたら､ 何らかのアクションを起こす3つの場所｡
And I love the way that it just simply reads like English.
そして､ 単純に英語のように読めるところが好きだ｡
If someone wants to convert, if they press convert button, it calls the optimize function.
もし誰かがコンバートを望むなら､ コンバートボタンを押せば､ 最適化機能が呼び出される｡
This is the inputs and that's the output.
これがインプットで､ これがアウトプットだ｡
If they press the Python run button, it executes Python.
Pythonの実行ボタンを押すと､ Pythonが実行される｡
The input is the Python code, the output is the python out, and the same for the C plus plus button
入力はPythonのコード､ 出力はPythonのout､ C plus plusボタンも同様｡
It should it look super simple.
超シンプルに見えるはずだ｡
And that's because it is super simple.
それは超シンプルだからだ｡
And with that we're going to launch it.
そして､ 私たちはそれを発表するつもりだ｡
Fingers crossed this is going to work beautifully for us.
これが僕らにとって見事に機能することを祈っているよ｡
All right so here is our user interface.
さて､ これがユーザー・インターフェースだ｡
Uh, and um, what you're seeing here of course, is the Python code for the simple, uh, pi calculation.
もちろん､ ここにあるのは単純な円周率計算のPythonコードだ｡
And why not?
なぜダメなんだ？
Let's just try doing it for, uh, for GPT.
GPTでやってみよう｡
You'll remember that's the C plus plus equivalent.
Cプラス・プラス相当と覚えておいてほしい｡
Let's run the Python variation.
Pythonのバリエーションを実行してみよう｡
If I remember right this is about eight seconds.
私の記憶が正しければ､ これは約8秒だ｡
So we have to wait for this to count to about eight.
だから､ これが8カウントになるのを待つしかない｡
And we should get the Python results.
そして､ パイソンの結果を得るべきだ｡
There it is 8.6 seconds.
そこに8がある｡  6秒｡
There is good old pi at least to some number of decimal places.
古き良き円周率は､ 少なくとも小数点以下何桁まで存在する｡
And now we'll run the C plus.
そして今度はCプラスを走らせる｡
Plus that came back from GPT four.
それにGPT4から戻ってきた｡
And great in 0.06 of a second a nice greater than 100 x improvement.
そして0点でも素晴らしい｡  秒の06は100倍以上の向上だ｡
Now one more time for Claude.
クロードのためにもう1度｡
We convert the the code courtesy of Anthropic's Claude.
Anthropicのクロードの好意でコードを変換した｡
Um, there it is.
あ､ あった｡
And now we will run Claude's C plus.
そして今度はクロードのCプラスを走らせる｡
Plus.
それに
And it narrowly beats, uh, GPT four again.
そして､ またGPT4に僅差で勝った｡
But I think it has this line in here, and maybe it has allowed it to be slightly faster.
でも､ このラインが入っていることで､ わずかに速くなったのかもしれない｡
Maybe Claude's code really is quicker.
クロードのコードの方が本当に速いのかもしれない｡
Um, they're so similar that I am suspicious.
うーん､ あまりに似ているので疑ってしまう｡
This is.
これがそうだ｡
This all gets optimized anyway by the compiler.
これはコンパイラによって最適化される｡
But it's possible this is consistently slightly faster.
しかし､ 一貫してわずかに速い可能性はある｡
So you may be a C plus plus expert.
だから､ あなたはCプラス・プラスの専門家かもしれない｡
That can tell me.
それは私に教えてくれる｡
And you may be able to try it yourself and satisfy yourself, whether on your architecture it is faster
そして､ 自分のアーキテクチャでそれが速いかどうか､ 自分で試して納得できるかもしれない｡
But anyway, that is not the point.
しかし､ とにかく､ それは問題ではない｡
What we're here to see is how does code quality measure up?
我々がここで見ているのは､ コードの品質がどの程度なのかということだ｡
Can it convert?
コンバートは可能か？
Does it make sense and is it any different?
それは理にかなっていて､ 何か違いがあるのだろうか？
Let's press the convert code button and see what happens.
コード変換ボタンを押して､ 何が起こるか見てみよう｡
So first of all as we know it's more it's got some chattiness to it.
だからまず第一に､ 僕らが知っているように､ それはもっとおしゃべりなんだ｡
It hasn't correctly stripped out its explanation.
その説明を正しく取り除けていない｡
So we will need to delete that.
だから､ それを削除する必要がある｡
But we'll let it get away with that.
しかし､ 私たちはそれを許す｡
We won't ding the code model for adding that extra.
そのような余計なものを加えたからといって､ コードモデルを非難するつもりはない｡
Remember, this is all streaming right now as as we watch it from the endpoint.
覚えておいてほしいのは､ これはすべてエンドポイントから見ている今現在のストリーミングだということだ｡
If I go over to here, I may need to refresh that.
こっちに行ったら､ リフレッシュする必要があるかもしれない｡
We should be seeing that we do.
私たちは､ 私たちがそうであることを確認しなければならない｡
We do indeed see a blip of CPU and GPU as it streams back the results, I love it.
確かに､ 結果をストリームバックするときにCPUとGPUが点滅するのが見える｡
Uh, and so here by now, uh, go down to the, uh, sorry to our gradient screen.
ええと､ ではここで､ ええと､ グラデーションのスクリーンに降りてください｡
Here we go.
さあ､ 始めよう｡
Uh, we have the, the, uh, full solution.
ええと､ 私たちは､ ええと､ 完全な解決策を持っています｡
So what we're going to do now is we're going to remove the stuff at the top, and we're going to remove
だから､ これからやることは､ 一番上にあるものを取り除き､ 最後にある必要のない説明を取り除くことだ｡
And we are going to run this C plus plus code to see how code Quinn has done.
そして､ このCプラスプラスのコードを実行し､ クインがどのような結果を残したかを確認する｡
Let's give it a try.
試してみよう｡
And it ran and it was fast.
そして走り､ 速かった｡
It was about the same as GPT four.
GPT4とほぼ同じだった｡
Oh, I imagine it's about the same.
同じぐらいだと思うよ｡
Uh, and I see it doesn't have that pragma thing in there, but it seems to have done a great job.
ええと､ プラグマは入っていないようですが､ 素晴らしい仕事をしてくれているようです｡
It's got the same answer.
同じ答えだ｡
And I think that is certainly a success for code.
そして､ それはコードにとって間違いなく成功だと思う｡
Quinn.
クインだ｡
Uh, and again, remember the difference in model parameters code Quinn running here with its 7 billion
そしてまた､ コード・クインがここで実行している70億のパラメーターと､
parameters and compared with the, uh, the uh, hundreds of, of of, uh, sorry, there are more than
GPT4やクロードが持っている2兆以上のパラメーターの違いを思い出してほしい｡
Uh, so let's now go back here and let's, let's, uh, raise the bar.
じゃあ､ ここに戻って､ ハードルを上げよう｡
Let's make the challenge harder.
チャレンジをもっと難しくしよう｡
Let's change this value to be the Python hard, the code which calculates the maximum subarray sum.
この値をPythonのハード､ つまり最大部分配列和を計算するコードに変更してみよう｡
And we will see now how our open source model can handle this complicated case.
そして､ 我々のオープンソースモデルがこの複雑なケースにどのように対処できるかをこれから見ていくことにしよう｡
So what's it doing its thing.
それで何をやっているんだ｡
So already there is a problem.
だからすでに問題がある｡
There is a problem.
問題がある｡
And that problem is that, uh, it has decided to reimplement the approach for generating random numbers,
そしてその問題とは､ 乱数を生成するためのアプローチを再実装することを決定し､
changing the approach that we had set with this, uh, LCG, um, technique for generating repeatable
この､ LCGで設定したアプローチを変更したことだ｡
Now, that's despite the fact that I very clearly put in the system prompt that it should not change
システム・プロンプトには､ 乱数生成に関する機能を変更してはいけないとはっきりと書いておいたにもかかわらず､
the functionality around random number generation.
だ｡
So again, I was not able to convince Coetquen to change that strategy.
だから今回も､ コエトケンにその戦略を変えるよう説得することはできなかった｡
Uh, you should experiment with this, see if you can do better.
ええと､ もっとうまくできるかどうか､ 実験してみるといいよ｡
But I was not able to do so myself with some experimenting.
しかし､ 私自身はいくつかの実験をしながらも､ そうすることはできなかった｡
Uh, it's almost finished.
もうすぐ終わるよ｡
There we go.
これでよし｡
It's done.
終わったよ｡
So we will take out what comes at the end, and we will take out what comes at the beginning.
だから､ 最後に来るものを取り除き､ 最初に来るものを取り除く｡
And now the moment of truth.
そして今､ 真実の瞬間が訪れる｡
We will run the C plus plus code from Code Kwan and scroll down.
コード・クワンのCプラス・プラス・コードを実行し､ 下にスクロールする｡
Uh, and what we find is, of course, that the number does not match.
それでわかったのは､ もちろん､ その数字が一致しないということだ｡
If you remember the the result from before.
以前の結果を覚えているのなら｡
So unfortunately, Code Kwan has not been successful in replicating the number, and that's no surprise.
だから残念ながら､ コード・クワンはこの数字を再現することに成功していない｡
That is because of course, it has, uh, got a its own random number generator.
それはもちろん､ 独自の乱数発生器を持っているからだ｡
Um, it's, um, done some, uh, some interesting stuff here.
ええと､ いくつか､ ええと､ 興味深いことをやっているんだ｡
It, uh, does appear to have potentially recognized the more efficient methodology, but since the
より効率的な方法を潜在的に認識しているように見えるが､ 数字が一致しないため､ 実際にすべてを正しく実行し､
numbers don't match, we can't validate that it has, in fact done everything correctly and got the
正しい数字を得たかどうかを検証することはできない｡
So unfortunately, unfortunately, I was so very hopeful.
だから残念ながら､ 残念ながら､ 私はとても期待していたんだ｡
Codeclan did Laudably Codeclan was able to pass the the pie test, the simple test, but Codeclan did
Codeclanは簡単なテストであるパイテストには合格したが､ Codeclanは難しいテストでつまずき､
stumble with the harder test and wasn't able to reproduce the same exact answer as the Python code,
Pythonコードと同じ答えを再現できなかった｡
So from that perspective, unfortunately, the frontier models come up on top.
そういう観点からは､ 残念ながらフロンティア・モデルが上位に来る｡
Clawed again for the win.
勝利のために再び爪を立てた｡
Uh, and Codeclan didn't quite make it.
コーデクランは間に合わなかった｡
I will see you next time for a wrap up.
それではまた次回､ 総括を｡